Long ago, there existed an extraordinary man wished for even more power.
He could live like the birds, dwell with the fish,
breathe like the trees, and move like the water.
But he could not face the sun.
So he created a stone mask.
One day he would conquer the sun.
And the world would be his!
Episode 26: "The Man Who Became A God"
Cars...
(ｼｭﾄﾛﾊｲﾑ)カーズは…
カーズは 溶岩へ突っ込んだか!?
Did Cars land in the magma?!
(ｼﾞｮｾﾌ)うあっ！
(ｶｰｽﾞ)OGooAHHHA！
You bastards...
お… おのれ…｡
We got him!
やった！
ガ… ガ… ガガ…｡
I-I need armor.
プ… プロテクターだ…｡
(ｶｰｽﾞ)貝や カニのような…
プロテクターを…➡
Like a clam or a crab...
...I'll make armor.
I'll cover myself.
み… 身にまとうのだ！
(ｼｭﾄﾛﾊｲﾑ)あっ！
ううっ…｡
(ｶｰｽﾞ)うお～…！
ぐわっ 効かぬ！
It's not working!
It's melted rock, idiot!
岩が溶けてるんだぜ！
It's over a thousand degrees!
溶岩の温度は 1,000度！
You're gonna burn to a crisp!
カスまで燃えて
なくなっちまわ～っ！
うお～っ！
おおっ！
So hot!
あちっ！
うっ!?
や… やっつけた！
T-That did it!
Finally!
ついに…｡
We finally took down Cars!
ついに カーズをやっつけたぞ～！
はぁ…｡
ハハハハッ…！
ハーッハッハッハ！
(地割れの音)
(ｼｭﾄﾛﾊｲﾑ･ｼﾞｮｾﾌ)あっ！
ジョジョ！
今のショックで 噴火が始まるぞ！
Jojo, that shock triggered an eruption!
Let's get to safety before celebrating!
安心して喜ぶのは
避難してからだぜ！
Good idea. Hang on tight!
おう！ しっかり つかまれよ！
(地割れの音)
うあっ…｡
あっ…｡
♬～
うああ… うあ～っ！
ああ…｡
うああ… うああ～っ！
ンンンンン… いい声だ｡➡
What a wonderful sound.
実に いい響きだ｡➡
It's music to my ears.
I've been longing to hear that sound from you, Jojo!
その絶叫を 聞きたかったぞ！
ジョジョ｡
ぐうう… うう…｡
Cars...but how?!
カーズ どうやって…｡ あ…｡
A bit of his shell.
(ｼｭﾄﾛﾊｲﾑ)これは カーズの…｡
(ｼｭﾄﾛﾊｲﾑ)
あっ！ そうか カーズのやつ…｡
I see. Cars...
フフ…｡
First, Cars covered himself in a shell like a crab.
〈カーズは 最初
カニや 貝のような➡
プロテクターを 身にまとった〉
But it was still organic.
〈だが あくまでも生物！➡
It couldn't withstand the magma's heat and burned away instantly.
そのプロテクターは
1,000度には耐えられず➡
あっという間に
燃え尽きてしまった〉
Cars 's secret was in a second layer of armor!
〈そこで！ 秘密は 次にまとった
プロテクターにある！➡
That second layer...
カーズの
第２のプロテクターは…〉
〈泡状だったのだ！➡
... was bubbles!
泡状ならば
溶岩と肉体の間に➡
The bubbles created a layer of air between Cars' body and the magma.
Heat from magma
Air
Body
空気の層ができ
熱は シャットアウト！➡
As the outer layer burned, more bubbles came up to replace it.
しかも 表面が燃えても➡
次から次へと
内側から 泡を生産していけば➡
This allowed Cars to survive in magma for a few minutes.
溶岩の中でも
数分は 活動可能なのだ！〉
The Earth gave birth to life.
〈地球は 生命をつくり出した｡➡
But now! Alas! In the end...
しかし…
ああ！ なんと！ ついに！➡
カーズは その地球をも
克服してしまった！〉
... Cars had conquered the Earth!
〈はるか昔 人間が歴史を持つ
ずっと以前の昔｡➡
Long, long ago, far earlier than man's first recorded history
その生き物たちは
進化の過程の中で➡
a certain group of creatures evolved on our planet.
この地球に出現した｡➡
They could only live at night, as they died when exposed to the sun.
その生き物たちは
夜しか 生きることができず➡
太陽の光に当たると
消滅してしまう｡➡
だから 彼らは地底に住んだ〉
So they lived below ground.
Even without the sun, they led long lives feeding on other living things.
〈太陽はなくとも 他の動物や➡
植物のエネルギーを
吸い取ることによって➡
長い年月 生きることができた〉
Early humans that appeared feared them as gods or demons.
〈やがて 現れた原始人は
彼らを 神や悪魔として恐れた｡➡
彼らは 死の確率が低いので
増殖の必要は 少なく➡
They rarely died, so they did not have many children and their population was small.
その生き物の個体数も
少なかった｡➡
They knew no strife and lived in peace.
だから 争いもなく
平和に暮らしていた〉
〈だが！➡
But then...
突然 そこに
天才が １人 生まれた〉
... a genius was born among them.
There is strength hidden in this body, abilities undreamed of.
《この体に 秘められた力➡
能力は
こんなものではないはず｡➡
もっと より強い力を》
I will unlock greater power!
〈天才は 石仮面を作った〉
The genius created a stone mask.
〈石仮面は
不死身の能力を もたらしたが➡
The mask granted him undying power, but he required more life energy.
より多くの
生命エネルギーを必要とした｡➡
つまり より多くの動物を
殺さなければならない｡➡
He had to consume more creatures to live.
放っておけば きっと➡
If left unchecked, he would eventually consume all life.
大地の 全ての生き物を
殺してしまうだろう｡➡
その生き物の一族は
石仮面を恐れた！➡
His brethren began to fear the mask and its gifted creator!
その天才を 恐れた！〉
《ん？》
His existence is a threat!
(一族１)
《やつが存在するのは 危険だ！》
He has to be removed from this world!
(一族２)《あいつを この地球から
消してしまわなくてはならない》
We have to destroy him!
(族長)《やつを
殺してしまわなくては！》
Fool! Don't you wish to conquer the sun?
《バカ者どもが！➡
太陽を克服したいと
思わないのか？➡
何者をも支配したいと
Don't you wish to rule over all?
あらゆる恐怖を
なくしたいと思わないのか!?》
Don't you wish to purge your fears?!
《では 滅びろ》
...If not, then disappear.
(一同)うお～！
〈その天才は
逆に 一族を皆殺しにし➡
The genius slaughtered all his brethren, including the parents who raised him.
自分を生んだ 親も殺した〉
He and one companion took the two surviving babies and left.
〈天才は
事実を知らぬ 赤ん坊 ２人に➡
仲間を１人連れ
長い旅に出た｡➡
彼が求める究極の力
完全な体を手に入れるために｡➡
They set off on a journey in search of ultimate power.
そして １万年後
天才は ついに手に入れたのだ！〉
And ten thousand years later, that power was in his hands!
He's a god. He's become a god.
神だ… やつは神になったんだ｡
Humans can't stand before a god!
我々 人間は
神にだけは勝てない！➡
Submission is our only option!
服従しかないんだ！
おお… おお… あっ…｡
ん？
何だって？
今 何か言ったか？ ジョジョ｡
What was that? Did you just say something, Jojo?
くっ…｡
うお～！
食らえ 波紋疾走！
Take this!
Overdrive!
Rip...ple?
波… 紋？
波紋疾走だと!?
Did you say "Ripple Overdrive"?
ぐぁあっ！
Jojo!
ジョジョ！
フッ…｡
う… うわあ！ この衝撃は!?
That shock!
と… 溶ける!? そんなバカな！
I'm melting! That's impossible!
My leg is melting!
俺の足が溶ける！
What? It's like he used...!
何!? その効果は!?
まさか!?
そうだ 波紋だよ！
It can't be!
It is! That was the Ripple, you dimwit!
この まぬけが！
I conquered the sun, and you still thought the Ripple was beyond me?!
太陽を克服した このカーズに
できないと思ったのか!?
この うすのろめが！
W-What?!
な… 何!?
And it looks like my Ripple is hundreds of times more potent than yours.
しかも その効果から見ると➡
貴様の 数百倍の強さの波紋を
練ることができる！
Hundreds of times more potent?!
｢数百倍の波紋｣だと!?
《つまり
太陽光で 焼かれたも同然｡➡
That's just like being burned by the sun itself!
肉が液体化し さらに
気化しているというわけか…》
His flesh is liquefying and then vaporizing!
So how do you like that taste of your own medicine?
どうだ？
自分で 波紋を受けた気分は？
うあ～っ！
んん～ 実にナイスな返事だ｡
An excellent response.
ぐあ～っ！
(ｶｰｽﾞ)
その声に免じて 楽にしてやろう｡
Well, let me ease your suffering.
Jojo!
(ｼｭﾄﾛﾊｲﾑ)ジョジョ！
ああ… はぁ…｡
《決定的だ｡➡
This is it. I'm going to die.
俺は 死ぬんだな… 決定的に》
It's over for me.
〈ジョジョは いともすんなり
それを受け入れた｡➡
Jojo accepted this fact completely.
He felt no fear, no pain, no regret.
恐怖はなかった｡
痛みもなかった｡➡
後悔もなかった｡➡
He thought, "I did all I could. "
｢やるだけやったんだからな｣
そう思った｡➡
圧倒的 悪の前にあるのは➡
Before the epitome of evil, all he could do was watch as the cold reality of death approached.
氷のように冷たい 冷静な
死にゆく自分を 見る目だった〉
〈シュトロハイムも同じだった｡➡
Stroheim was no different.
Unable to move, he understood how it felt to be a frog about to be swallowed by a snake.
動けなかった シュトロハイムは➡
生きながら 蛇に飲まれるカエルの
気持ちを 理解したと思った〉
This breathing technique...
この呼吸法だ｡
フフ… 波紋使いの貴様を➡
To send a Ripple-user like you into the black pit of death...
死という暗黒のふちに
突き落とす儀式には…｡
やはり この波紋が ふさわしい！
...what better method to use than the Ripple itself?!
《波… 紋…》
The Ripple...
コォー！
《俺の何百倍もの…》
... far greater than mine...
Sail into the infinite abyss of oblivion!
無限の谷底へ 溶けて流れ落ちろ！
The Ripple?!
《波紋だって？》
(ｼｭﾄﾛﾊｲﾑ)ああっ！
(ｶｰｽﾞ)何!?
What?!
(ｶｰｽﾞ)赤石!?
The Red Stone!
What?!
何!? 赤石!?
The Red Stone!
The Red Stone of Aja!
〈エイジャの赤石！➡
Why did Jojo hold the Red Stone toward Cars?
ジョジョは なぜ カーズの前に
赤石をかざしたのか➡
Even he didn't know!
彼自身 理解できなかった｡
無意識だった｡➡
It was merely instinctive. He felt the Red Stone being drawn toward the Ripple.
赤石が 波紋に吸い付くように
勝手に動いたと感じた〉
♬～
〈しかし ジョジョの
肉体は知っていた｡➡
But Jojo's body understood.
His body was always moving unconsciously to keep him alive.
生き抜こうとするジョジョの
♬～
肉体が動かしたのだ｡➡
Jojo's will to live pushed his body into action!
ジョジョの
♬～
生命の大車輪が➡
ジョジョの直感を
♬～
プッシュしたのだ！〉
せ… 赤石は
♬～
波紋増幅器だった…｡
T-The Red Stone is a Ripple amplifier.
♬～
(地鳴り)
(ｼｭﾄﾛﾊｲﾑ)はっ！
That energy made the volcano's eruption reach a sudden peak!
〈そして
♬～
そのエネルギーは➡
一気に噴火活動の
♬～
パワーとなって➡
頂点に達した！〉
♬～
(ｼｭﾄﾛﾊｲﾑ)うあ～！
(ｼｭﾄﾛﾊｲﾑ)ぐああっ！
T-The whole slab they were on was blasted into the sky!
が… 岩盤ごと
♬～
２人が押し上げられた～！
(ｶｰｽﾞ)RRRRRRYYY！
♬～
ぐうっ！
こ… これは… 確かに
♬～
すさまじいパワー！
S-Such tremendous force!
♬～
(ｶｰｽﾞ)RRRRRRYY！
But do you think a little eruption will be enough to get rid of me, Jojo?!
しかし このカーズが
♬～
噴火ごときで➡
消し飛ぶとでも思ったか!?
♬～
ジョジョ！
鳥に変身して 逃れてやる！
♬～
ぐっ…！
I'll become a bird to escape!
永遠にさよならだよ
♬～
ジョジョ！
Goodbye forever, Jojo!
♬～
うおっ…｡
さすが 地球のエネルギー！
That's the power of the Earth for you! It shot my arm all the way up here!
俺の腕を
♬～
ここまで吹き飛ばしたか！
Now, Cars!
♬～
そう カーズ！ 貴様は➡
Your next line is, "Was this all part of your plan, Jojo?!"
｢これも計算のうちか
♬～
ジョジョ！｣と言う｡
これも 計算のう…
Was this all part of your pl-
♬～
〈この一瞬が➡
For an instant, Cars was distracted by Jojo's arm and taunt! This instant would seal Cars' fate!
ジョジョの切断された腕に
♬～
気を取られた一瞬が➡
カーズの運命を分けた〉
♬～
Hot chunks of rock he could have dodged launched him higher!
〈よけられるはずの
♬～
下からの 灼弾岩に➡
さらに押し上げられた！〉
♬～
ぬお～っ！
Was this all part of your plan, Jojo?!
これも 計算のうちか!?
♬～
ジョジョ！
You're god damn right it was! I planned every little detail...
♬～
当たり前だぜ！
このジョジョは
♬～
何から何まで➡
計算ずくだぜ～！
♬～
R… RRREEKRRRRR！
From the very beginning!
♬～
《ホントは 違うけど➡
That's a total lie, but I'll say anything to piss off Cars, heh!
カーズが悔しがるなら
♬～
こう言ってやるぜ｡けっ！》
The material released in the eruption reached escape velocity!
〈灼熱の噴出物は
♬～
地球の動きを脱出して➡
大気圏外まで
♬～
吹っ飛んでいく｡➡
地球のパワーを
♬～
もってしても➡
If even the Earth's power couldn't kill Cars...
カーズを
♬～
殺すことはできない｡➡
しかし 地球は！➡
It would instead banish him to the depths of space!
カーズを大気圏外に
♬～
追放したのだ！〉
Stars?! I-Impossible!
(ｶｰｽﾞ)星!?
♬～
バ… バカな！
《終わった…》
It 's over.
《おばあちゃん
シュトロハイム➡
Granny...
Stroheim...
Uncle Speedwagon...
スピードワゴンのじいさん
スモーキー》
Smokey...
And Lisa Lisa...
《そして リサリサ
みんな あばよ…》
Farewell... everyone.
あっ… ジョ…➡
Jo...
Jojo!
ジョジョ～！
〈８時間後
生還したシュトロハイムは➡
Eight hours later, Stroheim was recovered alive, and reported the following to Speedwagon:
次のことを
スピードワゴンに語った〉
Feb
February
February 28,
February 28, 1939
Jo
Jose
Josep
Joseph
Joseph Jo
Joseph Joe
Joseph Joes
Joseph Joesta
Joseph Joestar
O
On
On I
On Iso
On Isola
On Isola di
On Isola di Vu
On Isola di Vul
On Isola di Vulca
On Isola di Vulcano
Has
Has Died
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
Has Died...
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
On Isola di Vulcano
February 28, 1939
Joseph Joestar
(ｶｰｽﾞ)RRRRRRRYYYEEEEEEEE！
I'm in outer space?!
宇宙空間だと!?
ふん！
I'll use jets of air to change my trajectory and return to Earth!
体内から 空気を噴出させて➡
その圧力抵抗で 軌道を変え
地球へ戻ってやるわ！
(凍る音)
(ｶｰｽﾞ)うぐっ…｡
ぎぃやあああああ！
だ… 駄目か!?
I-It's not working!
こ… 凍る！
I-I'm freezing!
ぐ… 空気が凍ってしまう｡
The air is freezing around me!
It turns to ice the moment it comes out of me!
外に出ると 凍ってしまう～！➡
ああっ！
き… 軌道を変えられん…➡
I-I can't change direction!
I can't go back!
戻れん！ あ～っ‼
〈カーズは
ニ度と地球へは 戻れなかった…〉
Cars would never return to Earth.
He became something between animal and mineral, has he floated through space forever.
〈鉱物と 生物の
中間の生命体となり➡
永遠に宇宙空間を
さまようのだ〉
And though he wished for death, he was unable to die.
〈そして 死にたいと思っても
死ねないので➡
Eventually Cars simply stopped thinking.
そのうち カーズは
考えるのをやめた〉
Outside New York City, April 1939
(牧師)天にまします 我らの父よ➡
Our Father who art in heaven,
御名を あがめさせたまえ➡
hallowed be thy name.
御国を来たらせたまえ➡
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done,
御心が天にあるように➡
地にもなさせたまえ｡
on earth, as it is in heaven.
♬～
Goodbye, Jojo.
(ｽﾓｰｷｰ)さようなら ジョジョ｡
考えてみると 知り合ったのは
ほんの半年前だったんだね｡
Now that I think of it, we only met six months ago.
But I'll always remember you.
でも…
決して忘れないよ 君のこと｡
(ｽﾓｰｷｰ)一生｡
Always.
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)エリナさん
さあ 冷えるといけない｡➡
Come, Erina, you mustn't catch cold.
もう帰りましょう｡
Let's go home.
(ｴﾘﾅ)もう少し…｡
Just a bit longer.
ヘヘヘ だ～れだ？
あっ…｡
Guess who?
(ﾘｻﾘｻ)あっ…｡
よお みんな！
Hey, everybody!
やっと
ニューヨークへ着いたってのに➡
I finally got to New York and nobody was there to meet me!
誰も 迎えに来てくれねえだろ!?
で 聞いたら みんな墓地で
葬式やってるって言うだろう？
So I heard you were all at a funeral. I looked high and low!
捜したぜ｡
よお リサリサ先生｡
傷は もういいのかい？
Hey, Master Lisa Lisa! Are you all healed up?
Messina, you're here too!
メッシーナもいるじゃあねえか｡
I wanted to ask Stroheim if he could beef up my hand with some cooler gadgets.
俺の方はよ やっぱり
シュトロハイムに頼んで➡
もっと 便利な腕にしてもらおうと
思ってんのよ｡
But it looks like the Germans were called to war.
でも ドイツとは
戦争やりそうだしなぁ…｡
Hey, now! What are you thinking?!
≪(ｶﾞｰﾄﾞﾏﾝ１)おい こら！
何者だ!? 貴様！
(ｶﾞｰﾄﾞﾏﾝ２)バカ者！
場所をわきまえろ 場所を！
This is a funeral, you idiot!
Who's an idiot?!
｢バカ者｣？ ｢バカ者｣だと!?
Hey, did you just call me an idiot?!
あんた！ 今 俺のこと
｢バカ者｣って言ったのか!?
(ｶﾞｰﾄﾞﾏﾝ１)まあまあ いいから
向こうへ行こうね｡
Just calm down. Let's go have a talk.
It's...
You're causing trouble for these nice folks.
(ﾒｯｼｰﾅ)お前は…｡
まさか…｡
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)ああ…｡
No way!
Hey! Don't start any trouble!
ああ…｡
てめえ 今 俺のこと
｢バカ者｣って言ったな～!?
You aren't getting away with calling me an idiot!
Jojo!
(一同)ジョジョ！
(ｽﾓｰｷｰ)うわ～！
ジョジョが生きてる～！
え？ ｢生きてる｣？
Jojo's alive!
Alive?
H-Hang on, now! What's with all the surprise?
ちょ… ちょっと待て｡
何で 俺を見て
そんなに驚くんだ？
It's like you've seen a ghost!
まるで おばけにでも…｡
What?! Why's my name on a headstone?!
ぎャにィィーッ！ 何で 俺の名が
墓に刻んであるんだ!?
ま… まさか この葬式は!?
≪(ｽｰｼﾞｰＱ)ジョジョ！➡
D-Don't tell me this is...
Jojo!
You're still recovering, so you shouldn't stand in the rain!
傷は まだ治ってないんだから
雨にぬれちゃあ 駄目よ！
(一同)ああ…｡
Take this.
(ｽｰｼﾞｰＱ)はい 傘｡
I-It's Suzi Q.
お… お前は スージーＱ｡
何だ？ その薬指のリングは…｡
What's that ring on her finger?
Y-You don't know about my wife, either?!
そ… それじゃあ
女房のことも知らねえのか？
Your wife?!
(一同)｢女房｣!?
Your wife? Oh, my!
女房だなんて そんな…➡
急に そういうふうに紹介されると
私…➡
Being introduced as your wife...
キャー！
It makes me blush!
恥ずかしいわ… ネ！
Right?
Don't "right" me!
｢ネ｣ じゃあねえ！
ん？
Hey... back when the volcano erupted...
おい お前 俺が火山で
岩ごと吹っ飛ばされたとき…➡
岩が
ちょうど 保護壁になってくれて➡
... the rock I was on shielded me and fell into the sea.
運良く 海に落下して➡
ヴェネチアの漁船に
救助されたことも…➡
A Venetian fishing boat picked me up.
そのあとの２週間➡
Then you nursed me back to health in Venice for two weeks.
ヴェネチアで お前に
ケガを介抱してもらったことも➡
みんな 知らねえみたいだぞ？
But no one knows any of that!
You sent that telegram, right?!
てめえ
ちゃんと電報 送ったんだろうな!?
あ～ で… 電報…｡
T-Telegram?
Yeah, you said you would!
そうだ！ 引き受けたよな!?
あ～…｡
(義手の音)
オホホホ…
そのキリキリは やめようね…｡
Could you stop with the clickity clicks?
I'm sorry! I forgot!
ごめんなさい！ 忘れちゃってた！
ぎゃあ～！ オーノー！
信じらんねえ！
Oh, no! Unbelievable!
何 考えてんだ あのアマ！ 待て！
(ｽｰｼﾞｰＱ)キャー！
What is that woman thinking?!
Get back here!
う… うわ～ん！
ジョジョが生きてたよ！
Jojo is alive!
だから
ごめんって言ってるでしょ｡
I said I'm sorry!
Sorry doesn't cut it!
ごめんで済むか!?
(ｽｰｼﾞｰＱ)いや～！ ウフフ…｡
ジョジョ…｡
Jojo...
Elizabeth Joestar
Lisa Lisa, a.k.a. Elizabeth Joestar, later told Jojo that she was his mother...
〈リサリサ ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ･ｼﾞｮｰｽﾀｰは
このあと➡
ジョジョに 自分が
母親であることを打ち明け➡
共に アメリカへ移住｡➡
While traveling back to America.
In 1948, she married a Hollywood screenwriter.
1948年に ハリウッド映画の
脚本家と再婚する〉
Erina Joestar
〈エリナ･ジョースターは
小学校の教師を続けるが➡
Erina Joestar continued her work as a teacher.
1950年 みんなに見守られながら➡
In 1950, at age 81, she died peacefully, surrounded by her loved ones.
81歳の生涯を 静かに閉じる〉
フフッ｡
Robert E. O. Speedwagon
Robert E. O. Speedwagon continued with his various enterprises
〈ﾛﾊﾞｰﾄ･E･O･ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝは➡
石油王 財団設立者として➡
さらに アメリカの経済界
医学界を発展させたが➡
and helped to further American science and medicine.
In 1952, he died of a heart attack at age 89.
1952年 心臓発作で死去｡➡
89歳 生涯 独身であった〉
He was never married.
〈スモーキー･ブラウンは
苦学しながらも 大学へ行き➡
Smokey Brown worked his way through college, majoring in political science.
Smokey Brown
政治学を修める｡➡
そして 後に 故郷ジョージアで
初の黒人市長となる〉
and became the first black mayor in Georgia, his home state.
〈ﾙﾄﾞﾙ･ﾌｫﾝ･ｼｭﾄﾛﾊｲﾑは
ジョジョに再会することなく➡
Rudolf von Stroheim never saw Jojo again.
1943年の
スターリングラード戦線で➡
Rudolf von Stroheim
In 1943, he died as a proud German soldier, fighting in the Battle of Stalingrad.
誇り高きドイツ軍人として
名誉の戦死を遂げる〉
...the best in the world!
(ｼｭﾄﾛﾊｲﾑ)世界一ィィィ！
〈そして 時代は流れる〉
And so, time marches forward...
JFK International Airport, New York, 1987
... towards a new generation.
〈世代は交代する〉
〈ジョジョは…〉
And Jojo...
うっ！ ああ…｡
Oh, I bumped you. Are you okay?
(男性)あ～ ぶつかっちまった｡➡
痛かったかい？ おじさん｡
困ったな｡➡
Oh, dear. You should watch where you're going.
向こう向いている
あんたが 悪いんだぜ｡
You're right. I'm fine though.
いや いいってことです｡
間違いは 誰にでもありますよ｡
We all make mistakes.
あっ ちょっと待って｡
あんた 日本人か？
Wait a minute. Are you Japanese?
Yeah, why?
ああ そうだけど｡
なら 話は別じゃ！
Well that changes everything!
ギニャー！
けっ！
(ｱﾅｳﾝｽ)東京行き 15時８分発…
Alitalia flight 285 for Tokyo is now boarding.
I repeat. Alitalia flight 285 for Tokyo is now boarding.
うう…｡
大切な一人娘が
日本人と結婚して もう20数年｡
My only daughter has been married to a Japanese man for over 20 years now.
Why did she get married on the other side of the world?
何で 地球の裏側まで
嫁いでいかなきゃあならないんだ｡
孫なぞ
わしの顔なんか 忘れちまっとる！
I bet my own grandson wouldn't even recognize my face!
Unforgivable! I hate the damn Japanese!
許さん！ 大切な娘を 日本人め！
(男性)うう… いで～ いで～よ！
でも…｡
Although...
...these Walkman things are pretty cool.
ウォークマンは好きだがね｡
♬(ｴﾝﾃﾞｨﾝｸﾞﾃｰﾏ)
Shijima no soko kara
From out of the stillness
♬ 静寂の底から
Mezameru sono hashira tachi
The Pillars of the past are awakening
♬ 目覚めるその柱たち 時を越え
Toki wo koe
To the dawn of a new day
Shinku no chishio ga
The river of crimson blood within you
♬ 深紅の血潮が
♬ 立ち上がる勇気を
Tachiagaru yuuki wo hikiawaseru
Carries with it the courage to stand and fight
♬ 惹きあわせる
Uketsugu ai wo sadame to yobu nara
Even if the love I feel is just part of my legacy...
♬ 受け継ぐ愛を 宿命と呼ぶなら
♬ 微笑む目で 次の手を
Hohoemu me de tsugi no te wo
I'll still be smiling as I stay one step ahead
♬ 闇を欺いて 刹那を躱して
Yami wo azamuite setsuna wo kawashite
Defying the darkness and dodging death at every turn
♬ 刃すり抜け奴らの間隙を突け
Yaiba surinuke yatsura no suki wo tsuke
Slipping past the knife's edge and striking when you least expect
♬ つらぬいた信念が 未来を拓く
Tsuranuita omoi ga mirai wo hiraku
The emotions running through me blaze a path to the future...
Like a bloody storm
♬ Like a Bloody Storm
熱くLike a Bloody Stone
Atsuku like a bloody storm
Burning like a bloody storm
Ketsumyaku ni kizamareta innen ni
When the time comes to end the vendetta carried by our blood
♬ 血脈に刻まれた因縁に
Ukiagaru kienai hokori no kizuna
Remember that the bonds of pride will carry you through any storm
♬ 浮き上がる消えない誇りの絆
Nigirishimete
So hold them close
♬ 握りしめて
Part 2: Battle Tendency
The End
Atlantic Ocean, near the Canary Islands, 1983
(ﾄﾚｼﾞｬｰﾊﾝﾀｰ１)や… やった！
ついに 引き揚げたぞ！
Y-Yahoo! We finally got it!
R-Relax! Just bring it up!
(ﾄﾚｼﾞｬｰﾊﾝﾀｰ２)お… 落ち着け！
慎重に 引き揚げるんだ！
It's a hundred-year-old treasure chest!
(ﾄﾚｼﾞｬｰﾊﾝﾀｰ１)
100年前に沈んだ 宝の箱だ！
L-Let's pop it open!
(ﾄﾚｼﾞｬｰﾊﾝﾀｰ２)
は… 早く開けようぜ！
♬～
Some-Stuffs
Original Translation:
Timing:
Typesetting:
Editor:
Quality Check:
Encoding:
Raw Provider:
Mudasubs (Episode 1-14)
Retail (Episode 15-26)
Fadeout4
Tonitonichopchop
Mazrim
Fadeout4
Wrrry